https://www.industry.nsw.gov.au/privacy

Privacy statement
The statements below apply to any content such as pages, documents, videos, images, sound files and computer code (the "Material") created by the NSW Department of Industry ("the department") for its websites.General privacy policyThe New South Wales Government's privacy practices are regulated by the New South Wales Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act 1998 (the Act). For more information contact the Office of the NSW Privacy Commissioner (www.lawlink.nsw.gov.au/privacynsw)NSW Department of Industry will only collect personal information for a lawful purpose which directly relates to our primary function as a NSW Government agency and for obtaining feedback about the effectiveness of our services. The department will not collect any more information than is necessary for it to fulfil these functions.The department will not disclose your personal information to anyone without your consent unless legally required to do so.Anyone engaged to collect, store or use personal information for the department will be required to comply with the Information Protection Principles of the Act as part of their terms of engagement.For more information on how the department does this, refer to our Privacy Management Plan.Storage of private informationThe department takes all reasonable steps to protect the security of any personal information held, be it stored in electronic or hard copy format. Except in the circumstances set out in the Act, you may request access to your personal information held by the department. Access can be arranged by contacting:Governance & Information Access UnitNSW Department of IndustryBox K348HAYMARKET NSW 1240Phone: +61 2 9934 0660E: privacy@industry.nsw.gov.auEmail addressesEmail addresses are recorded when an email message is sent to the department or when a user subscribes to an online mailing list.These email addresses are stored electronically in accordance with standards and authorities under the New South Wales State Records Act 1998. An email address is only used for the purpose for which it is provided and is not added to any unauthorised mailing list or disclosed to other organisations unless you request that this to be done.If you have subscribed to one of the department's online mailing lists, you can easily remove your email details from the list by unsubscribing. Each mailing list provides clear instructions on how to unsubscribe.Cookies and tracking pixelsWhat are cookiesCookies are small text files that sent back to your computer’s hard drive by websites that you visit.Cookies are created when a user's browser loads a particular website. The website sends information to the browser which then creates a text file. Every time the user goes back to the same website, the browser retrieves and sends this file to the website's server.Cookies allow us to recognise our registered users, count visitor numbers and find out how they navigate the site, helping us make changes so you can find what you’re looking for more quickly.Cookies may also be used in conjunction with pixel tags to determine pages that have been visited on our sites.How to control and delete cookiesYou can change your cookie settings whenever you want to and, unless you change them, we’ll assume you are happy to receive all cookies on our website.If you wish to restrict or block the cookies, you can do this through your browser settings. The “Help” function within your browser should tell you how.You can also set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to allow it. However, if you decide to not accept cookies, some of the department's web pages may not display properly or you may not be permitted to access certain information.Tracking pixels'Pixels' means the use of use of pixels (1 x 1 pixel images) to track traffic such as web page visits and link clicks. The data collected will help us to better tailor our content for audiences. All information collected is de-identified and we will never collect or disclose any personal information.For more information read the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner’s targeted advertisingAlternatively, you may wish to visit www.allaboutcookies.org which contains details on how to delete cookies from your computer as well as more general information about cookies.Facebook Pixel useThe Department uses Facebook remarketing pixels to aid in customised, targeted follow-up advertising. The Department may display interest-based ads to you when you are using Facebook through Facebook’s Custom Audience Tool. This tool allows us to personalise our ads based on your interests, demographics, location and any previous interactions with us.This website uses the Conversion Tracking Facebook Pixel to allow us to follow your actions once you have been redirected to the website via clicking on one of our Facebook ads. This assists us in recording the effectiveness of Facebook ads for reporting and market research purposes.The data collected through the Facebook Pixel and provided to us is aggregated and remains anonymous, meaning that we cannot see the personal information of the individual user. However, the collected data is also saved and processed by Facebook and used in accordance with Facebook’s Data Use Policy.The Department may also share information about your use of this website and your interactions with our Facebook ads with our trusted social media, advertising and web analytics partners, including Google Analytics.Facebook Conversion Tracking also allows Facebook and its partners to show you advertisements on and outside Facebook. A cookie will be saved onto your computer for these purposes.Please visit Facebook Ad Preferences if you wish to revoke your permission.Online transactions using credit cardsThe department understands the security concerns surrounding online financial transactions and has developed a safe and secure environment to address these concerns.The department does not store credit card details from the listed websites in its computer systems.The department uses encryption software to protect credit card information and to provide transaction security. This means that all personal information, including name, address and credit card number, cannot be read as a transaction travels across the internet from your computer to the department's computers, or from the department's computers to a bank.Information received via feedbackThe department may provide feedback facilities on their sites to allow users to provide input into the future development of the sites and to comment on the provision of service by the department. The provision of personal details on feedback is optional.Users may provide personal details for the purpose of receiving a reply to their feedback. This information will only be used for the purpose for which it was provided. We will not add your email address or name to any mailing list.The department may publish aggregated information about feedback on the site, but will ensure that this aggregated information cannot be used to identify individual users.Logging of visitsWhen you access any of the pages on the Listed Websites, we automatically record information that identifies, for each page accessed:the IP (Internet Protocol) address of the machine which has accessed ityour top-level domain name (for example .com, .gov, .au, .uk etc.)the address of your serverthe date and time of your visit to the sitethe pages accessed and documents downloadedthe previous site visited andthe type of browser and operating system you have used.The information collected during each visit is aggregated with similar logged information and published in reports in order for the department to manage its website services and identify patterns of usage of the sites. This will assist us in improving the department's sites and the services offered on them.The department will not disclose or publish information that identifies individual computers, or potentially identifies sub-groupings of addresses, without consent or otherwise in accordance with the New South Wales Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act 1998.ExceptionsThe department will collect, use and disclose more extensive information than stated above in the following circumstances:unauthorised attempts to access files which are not publicly availableunauthorised tampering or interference with files on the listed websitesunauthorised attempts to index the contents of the listed websitesattempts to intercept messages of other users of the listed websitescommunications which are defamatory, abusive, vilify individuals or groups or which give rise to a suspicion that an offence is being committed andattempts to otherwise compromise the security of the web server, breach the laws of the State of New South Wales or Commonwealth of Australia, or interfere with the use of the listed websites by other users.The department reserves the right to make disclosures to relevant authorities where the use of the listed websites raises a suspicion that an offence is being, or has been, committed. In the event of an investigation, the department will provide access to data to any law enforcement agency that may exercise a warrant to inspect our logs.The department may initiate proceedings in relation to any loss or damage suffered as a result of unauthorised use of information or any of the above circumstances.Disclosure may also occur where it is lawfully authorised or required under any act, other law or statutory agency or foreign body.Linked websitesThe department does not have any responsibility for the privacy policies or practices of third party sites linked to from the listed websites.Questions or complaintsIf you have any questions about privacy, or the application of this Privacy Policy or a request for access to information held please contact:Governance & Information Access UnitNSW Department of IndustryBox K348HAYMARKET NSW 1240Phone: +61 2 9934 0660E: privacy@industry.nsw.gov.auWill this policy be updated over time?Due to the developing nature of privacy principles for online communication, this policy may be modified or expanded in light of new developments or issues that may arise from time to time. The amended policy will be posted to this site and will operate from the time it is posted.
Back to top
Page link: https://www.industry.nsw.gov.au/privacy
×
Modal Heading
Close
